嗯
Huh?
太好了
Yes!
醒醒
Wake up!
啊
Ah!
呃
Uh! Uh!
伙计们 快醒醒
Guys, wake up!
呃啊
Urggh!
怎么了 多尼
What is it, Donnie?
我在之前和斯普林特老师建立的传输中
I traced the binary code from the transmission I established
追踪了二进制代码定位到了信号源
with Master Splinter and located the source.
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter!
父亲
Father!
他怎么不说话
Why ain't he talking?
多尼 怎么回事
Donnie, what gives?
你们看到的只是斯普林特老师的一个碎片
What you're looking at is just one small piece of Master Splinter.
一个只包含他部分实体的数据片段
A data bit that contains only a fragment of his essence.
呃 多尼 把我当作麦奇重新解释一遍
Uh, Donnie, explain it to me like I was Mikey.
嘿
Hey.
这就是我过去几周一直在研究的东西
It's what I've been working on these past few weeks.
试图查明斯普林特老师发生了什么
Trying to find out what happened to Master Splinter
在病毒维拉用分解射线击中他之后
after Viral blasted him with that decompiler.
和我猜测的一样
And it's as I suspected.
斯普林特老师身处网络空间
Master Splinter's in cyberspace.
显然被分裂成了成千上万个这种数据碎片
Apparently separated into what could be thousands of these tiny bits.
他一定是和维拉一起被传送到了那里
He must have been transported there with Viral
她就是那时候逃脱的
when she made her escape.
仍然有许多问题悬而未决
There is still so many questions that remain.
有许多变量需要确定
So many variables to determine.
无论如何 我们的下一步行动已经明确了
But even so, our next move is clear.
是吗
It is?
是的 我们要进入网络空间获取那些数据
Yes, we're rescuing Master Splinter
来拯救斯普林特老师
by going into cyberspace and getting those bits.
忍者时间到
It's ninja time!
在城市中 就在现场
In the city, on the scene
地下与缝隙之间
Underground and in between
有一支强悍的绿色英雄战队
There's a mean, green team of heroes
超乎你的想象
Like you've never seen
当恶棍与忍者神龟交战之时
And when the villains and turtles fight
出发
Let's go!
这将是一出好戏
It's gonna be one shell of a sight
你知道神龟们守护着你
You know the turtles got your back
回到下水道
Back, back to the Sewer
忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
回到下水道
Back, back to the Sewer
少年变异忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
点名
Roll call!
莱昂纳多
Leonardo!
多纳泰罗
Donatello!
拉斐尔 米开朗基罗
Raphael, Michelangelo!
我爱当一只神龟
I love bein' a turtle
有一支强悍的绿色英雄战队
There's a mean, green team of heroes
你从未见过
That you've never seen
他们正全力以赴
And they're doin' everything they can
出发
Let's go!
粉碎施莱德的邪恶计划
To stop evil Shredder's plan
没错 神龟归来
Oh yeah, the turtles are back
回到下水道
Back, back to the Sewer
忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
回到下水道
Back, back to the Sewer
少年变异忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
回到下水道
Back, back to the Sewer
理论上 就像2105年的传送车床
So in theory, just like the Transindental Lathe
能以每毫秒百万部件的速率
from 2105 works the molecular transference at a rate
完成分子转移
of a million parts per millisecond,
这个传送门装置能使我们瞬间进入网络空间
this portal device will make our trip into cyberspace instantaneous.
至少 理论上是的
At least in theory.
呃
ALL: Uuuh.
我带来了一些特殊的网络装备
I'm bringing along some special cyber gear.
我对薇拉和她的能力做了粗略研究
I've made a cursory study of Viral and her abilities,
并尽量融入了一些新的防御程序
and I've incorporated as much as I could into some new defensive programs.
这样我们就能应对各种情况
So we'll be ready for anything.
前提是我的所有计算都正确
That is if all my calculations were correct.
但我想我们马上就能知道了
But I suppose we'll find out soon enough.
马上?
We will?
好吧 准备好了吗
All right, ready or not!
哇 多尼 你不觉得太草率了吗
Whoa, Donnie, don't you think you're rushing into this?
也许吧
Maybe.
但是对斯普林特老师来说 时间可能很紧迫
But time could be a factor for Master Splinter.
我们根本不知道他在网络空间能存在多久
We simply don't know how long he can last in cyberspace,
更别说他现在还处于分解状态
let alone in his decompiled state.
我可不想干等着看结果
And I'm not gonna wait around to find out.
呃
Ugh.
多尼 等等
Donnie, wait!
快 我们得追上他
Come on, we're going after him.
呃 呃 那些跨次元传送
Uh, uh, all that talk about Transindental transfer
和分子毫秒级的概念让我脑子疼
and molecular milliseconds made my brain hurt.
首先你得有个脑子 麦奇
First you gotta have a brain, Mikey.
现在行动吧
Now let's move.
但愿多尼知道他在做什么
And let's hope Donnie knows what he's doing.
终于能清静一会儿了
At last, a little peace and quiet.
偏偏在这种糟糕时刻 我也无福消受
Not that I can enjoy it in this dreadful time.
哇 这地方太酷了
Wow, this place is too cool.
要我说的话 有点阴森森的
Kinda creepy, if you ask me.
搞什么名堂
What the shell?
当心
Look out!
大家靠近我
Stay close to me, guys.
有很多地方需要我们去查找
We've got a lot of ground to cover.
分解器的效应将斯普林特老师的
The effects of the decompiler spread
数据碎片打散到了网络空间的各个地方
Master Splinter's data bits all over cyberspace.
哇 我的赛博伙伴们
Whoa, my fellow cybernauts,
出自《星际迷航》
"我们正勇敢地前往从未有龟踏足的领域"
we are bravely going where no turtles have ever gone before.
数字世界
the digital world!
网络空间
Cyberspace!
我们做的任何事都是从未有乌龟做过的
No turtles have ever done any of the things we do.
一针见血
Touché.
这些都是些什么东西
What is all this stuff?
游戏节点、数据请求序列、数据代码
Gaming nodes, online reference streams, data codes.
构成互联网的一切
Everything that makes up the Internet.
我知道它会很庞大
I knew it would be big.
但这也太惊人了
But this.
在这儿行动都很困难
Gonna be tough getting around in here,
更别说找东西了
let alone finding anything.
这就是我为什么熬了这么多夜
That's why I've been working so many late nights.
看好了…代码跑车
Behold...the code runner.
哦 哦 哦
Oh, oh, oh.
我想我坠入爱河了
I think I'm in love.
哦 我想要一个 我也想要一个
Ooh, I want one, I want one.
拉夫 麦奇 来认识一下赛博推土机
Raph, Mikey, say hello to the cyber ripper.
我给每辆车都装了追踪装置
I've outfitted each vehicle with tracking devices
还有防御功能
and defensive capabilities.
而且我想你会对它们的操控性
And I think that you'll be quite pleased
感到非常满意
with how they handle.
它们被设定为
They're configured to
靠这个领域中流动的代码脉冲运行
run on code pulses that float through the terrain here.
因此我们可以在几乎任何地方赛一场
So we should be able to race them pretty much anywhere.
赛车
Race 'em?
总算谈到我的领域了
Now you're taking my language.
他是在跟你说话呢 拉夫
He would be talking to you, Raph,
如果他说的是当第二名这件事
if he were talking about being second.
希望你喜欢看我的背影
I hope you like looking at my back.
哼 我们走着瞧
Huh, we'll see about that.
你们还需要更早的起步才行
You'll need more of a head start than that.
这才是我说的网上冲浪
Now this is what I call surfing the net.
哈哈 太棒了
Ha, ha, that was awesome.
爽
Sweet!
好耶
Yeah!
别闹了 伙计们
Enough horsing around, guys.
记住 我们是来找斯普林特老师的
Remember, we're here for Master Splinter.
看样子 我们马上就能追踪到
And from the looks of it, we're closing in
他数据碎片发出的能量信号了
on the energy signature of his data bits.
得分
Score!
看来我们找到了三个
Looks like we found three of 'em.
奇怪
Strange.
又出现一次能量波动
There's another surge.
而且与斯普林特的数据不匹配
And it doesn't match Splinter's bits.
事实上 它的特征类似于...
In fact, its signature is similar to...
维拉的 只是更强大
Viral's, only much more powerful.
我们得小心点
We should be careful.
放松点 多尼
Relax, Donnie.
这可是互联网
It's the Internet.
到处都有能量激增
There are energy surges all over the place.
快点
Come on!
看 他们在那儿
Look, there they are.
嗯
Huh?
啊
Ah!
呃
Uh.
不可能
No way.
难道是
Is that?
斯莱德
The Shredder?
但这怎么可能
But how?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我们是来找斯普林特老师的
But we're here for Master Splinter,
不是来打架的
not to fight.
是吗
Yeah?
你跟他说吧
Tell it to him.
乌龟们 我得知你还活着
Turtles, I learned that you were still alive.
但没想到会在这里见到你们
But I am not expected to see you here.
彼此彼此 铁桶头
Likewise, bucket head.
我看你比以往更加扭曲了
I see you're looking more twisted than ever.
上次听说你时 你还被囚禁在
Last we heard, you were in prison
在某个遥远的、毫无假释机会的小行星上
in some far off asteroid with zero chance of parole.
我不知你所言何事
I know not of what you speak.
但你早该明白
But you should have learned by now
没人能阻止施莱德
that nothing can stop The Shredder.
我早已为任何不测做好准备
I've long since been prepared for any contingency.
你看 通过将乌创技术
SHREDDER: You see, by an amalgamation
与你们可悲的地球机械相结合
of Utrom Technology and your pathetic earth machinery,
我很早就创建了自己的数字容器
I long ago created a digital engram of myself,
一个持续更新的备份程序
a backup that was constantly renewed
以备躯体发生不测之时得以复活重生
and could be resurrected should anything happen to my capoeira form.
这份记忆印迹曾被安全封存于数据密室
This engram was locked away for safe keeping in a data vault
直至某种奇异的网络生命体试图入侵
until some strange cyber lifeform attempted to break
触发了密室的防御机制
into the vault and activated its defense mechanism.
正是这个机制将我释放
A mechanism that released me.
使我得以吸收并掌控这具病毒躯体
Allowed me to absorb and commandeer this viral being
成就了如今你所见的模样
so that I am as you see me now!
我本该好奇你如何抵达此地
I would have wondered how you came to be here
闯入这片数字领域
in this digital realm.
但此刻已无关紧要
But it matters not.
你们很快就不存在了
You soon won't be.
既然你已落入我的掌控之中
Now that I have you within my grasp,
你将被摧毁
you shall be destroyed!
呃 多尼
Uh, Donnie,
有赛博武器吗
Uh, Donnie, cyber weapons?
红色按钮
Red button.
这才像话嘛
That's more like it.
让我们来一场赛博大战
Let's kick some cyber shell.
呀
Yah!
呃 啊
Uh, ah!
啊
Ah!
为什么每次重逢 这家伙都变得更厉害
Why does this guy get harder to fight every single time we meet him?
唉
Ugh.
你毫无胜算
You have no hope of defeating me.
在这数字领域 我至高无上
In this digital domain, I reign supreme.
我开始觉得他说得有道理
I'm starting to think he has a point.
多尼 你能带我们离开这里吗
Donnie, can you get us out of here?
这边走
This way!
后会有期 斯莱德脑袋
Later, Shred Head!
我可不这么认为
I think not.
啊
Ah!
救命
Help!
麦奇
Mikey!
你哪儿也去不了
You are going nowhere!
坚持住
Hold on!
我找不到可以抓的东西了
Having trouble finding something to hold onto to.
呃
Ugh!
啊
Ah!
啊 啊 啊
Ah, ah, ah!
我还以为你在带我们离开这里
I thought you were getting us out of here.
这里还是网络空间
This is still cyberspace.
是的 没错
Yes, it is.
我们正在一个会计软件程序里
We're in an accounting software program
藏在数道防火墙之后
behind several firewalls.
这是我情急之下能找到最安全的地方
The safest place I could find at the spur of the moment.
我们为什么还留在这里
And we're still here because?
因为斯普林特老师的三块碎片在这里
Because those three bits of Master Splinter are here.
不拿到它们我们绝不离开
And we're not leaving without them.
呃 除非你没注意到
Uh, unless you missed it,
我刚刚差点就被炸成电子尘埃了
I almost got zapped into cyber dust just a second ago
我们最爱的尖头反派居然出现了虚拟版本
by a virtual version of our favorite pointy-headed villain!
麦奇说得对
Mikey's right.
既然要留下
If we're gonna stay,
我们就得想办法对付那个电子版的施莱德
then we need to find a way to take on that cyber Shredder.
我或许有个主意
And I may just have one.
我本希望在实地测试前
I was hoping to work out some of the bugs
能解决一些程序漏洞
before attempting a field test.
但危急时刻只能铤而走险
But desperate times call for desperate measures.
或者说眼下这种情况——
Or in this case--
赛博装甲
Cybernaut armor.
耶哈
ALL: Yeah-ha!
难道没有其他尺寸可选吗
It doesn't come in any other sizes?
呃 我早说过这套系统还有些漏洞
Uh, I told you there were a few bugs.
听着 这套赛博装甲应该能帮上忙
Now, listen, this cyber armor should help.
但是在这里想要有胜算的话
But if we're gonna stand a chance here,
我们必须利用身处网络空间的优势
we have to take advantage of the fact that we're in cyberspace.
现实世界的规则未必适用
The rules of the real world don't necessarily apply.
我们要开始像网络行者那样思考
We have to start thinking like cybernauts.
没有检测到电子施莱德的踪迹
I'm not picking up any trace of the cyber Shredder.
那我们快去取
Then let's go get
斯普林特老师的三块碎片吧
those three bits of Master Splinter.
我的机载扫描仪显示它们就在前方
My onboard scanner indicates they're up ahead.
仍然没有施莱德的踪影
Still no sign of The Shredder.
呃 留神注意
Uh, keep an eye out.
我需要几分钟创建一个管道
I need a few minutes to create a conduit to store
将这些数据位存储在安全的地方
these data bits in a safe place.
我们罩着你 多尼
We got you covered, Donnie.
目前还算——
So far, so--
嗯
Huh?
快点 多尼 我们有客人了
Hurry up, Donnie, we've got company.
十二点钟方向有人来了
Coming in at 12 o'clock.
还需要点时间
Need more time.
等一下
Wait a minute.
六点钟方向有人朝我这边来了
I've got him coming in from 6 o'clock.
呃 按我这玩意儿显示 他正从这边过来
Uh, according to my thingy, he's coming from this way.
哦 真令人龟壳疼
Oh pain in my shell!
他干嘛不直接像乌龟一样出来打一场
Why doesn't he just come out and fight like a turtle?
就差一点了
Almost got it.
是吗 还有斯莱德马上也要赶过来了
Yeah, well, The Shredder's about to get us, too.
来了
Here it comes.
嘿
Hey!
啊
Ah!
数据位
The data bits.
起来吧 乌龟们
Rise, turtles.
起来受死吧
Rise and be destroyed.
还是那个老样子 施莱德 还是那么聒噪
Same old Shredder, same old noise.
我来找你了 斯普林特老师
I'm coming for you, Master Splinter.
我需要更多时间来保护数据碎片
I need more time to secure the data bits.
去吧
Go for it.
与此同时 我们来给你的战甲做实地测试
Meanwhile, we'll give your cybernaut armor that field test.
呃
Uh!
这次可不会了
Not this time.
我们现在已经准备好了
We're ready for you now.
是这样吗
Is that so?
呃 呃 啊
Uh, uh, ah!
看来我没能像网络行者那样思考
Guess I wasn't thinking like a cybernaut.
思考从来就不是你的强项
Thinkin' never was your strong suit.
让我来示范该怎么做
Let me show you how it's done.
他刚才——
Where did he--
多尼说这里的规矩不一样
Donnie said the rules are different here.
得好好利用这一点
Gotta take advantage.
得像网络行者一样思考
Gotta think like a cybernaut.
嗯 嗯
Uh, uh!
拖住他 我这边快搞定了
Keep him busy, I'm almost done here.
呃 呃
Uh, uh!
我打中他了
I got him.
我实实在在地...
I actually--
呃
Uh!
唉 本来搞定了的
Well I had him.
如果你能打中他 那我也能
If you can hit him, I can hit him.
呃 目前还算顺利
Uh, so far so good.
啊
Ah!
哈
Ha!
可怜的虫子
Pathetic worm.
你伤不了我
You cannot harm me.
像网络行者一样思考
Think like a cybernaut.
是的
Yes!
不
No!
呃
Ugh!
多尼 情况如何
Donnie, status?
还没好
Not yet.
抱歉 我从来没做过这个
Sorry, I've never done this before.
啊
Ah!
干得漂亮 李奥
Way to go, Leo!
蠢货 你们休想打败我
Fools, you cannot destroy me.
但我能消灭你们
But I can destroy you!
呃 多尼 你搞定了没
Uh, Donnie, are you done yet?
再给我一点时间 兄弟们
Just a little more time, guys.
这是一个缓慢而复杂的过程
It's a slow, intricate process.
你能既缓慢又复杂地加快速度吗
Can you be slow and intricate faster?
我的孩子
My son.
父亲
Father?
多纳泰罗
Donatello!
我绝不会辜负你
I won't fail you.
这次不会
Not this time.
我们准备好了
We're good to go.
我在走了...在走了
I'm going! I'm going!
呃
Uh!
啊
Ah!
麦奇 不要
Mikey, no!
呃
Uh!
啊
好大的胆子
You dare!
拿到数据碎片了
I have the data bits.
那咱们快撤
Then let's get out of here.
去救麦奇
Get Mikey.
我来对付斯莱德 和救拉斐尔
I'll take care of The Shredder and get Raph.
呃
Uh.
哦
Oooh!
谢了 兄弟
Thanks, bro.
这边走
This way!
快点
Come on!
得抓紧了
This is gonna be close!
别管我
Don't mind me.
我只是个金属减速带
I'm just a metallic speedbump
为了方便你们而困在这里了
stuck here for your convenience.
拉夫 你没事吧
Raph, you okay?
没事
Yeah.
但下次 我来开车
But next time, I'm driving.
而且很快就会有下次
And the next time will be soon.
里面还有更多斯普林特老师的数据碎片
There are a lot more of Master Splinter's data bits in there.
我们绝不会罢休 直到把最后一个也拿到手
And we're not gonna stop until we get every last one.
即使施莱德就在里面等着我们
Even if The Shredder is in there waiting for us.
乌龟们有一个网络传送门
The turtles have a cyber-portal.
有意思
Interesting.
非常有意思
Very interesting.